<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Broker Team</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams is to be your best resource for Houston real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams, your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 12:02:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 12:02:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Are You a Seller Who’s Not Sold on Staging?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rc5DkDsIOVc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s why the power of staging shouldn’t be overlooked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a fun little experiment for the video above: Would you, as a homebuyer, prefer to buy the home at 0:13, or the one at 0:16? And why? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s the same home in both pictures; staging does wonders! &lt;strong&gt;Did you know the Houston Broker Team offers staging as part of our services?&lt;/strong&gt; Our in-house staging company can stage vacant and occupied properties and create a plan tailored to your specific spaces. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this competitive real estate market, we help you stand out. That means less time on the market and more money in your pocket! If you have questions about how to sell a home in this market, give me a call or send me an email today; I’d be more than happy to have a chat with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 06:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-are-you-a-seller-whos-not-sold-on-staging.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-are-you-a-seller-whos-not-sold-on-staging.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Should You Contact a Realtor or Lender First?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z2QsjwaE0KI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which comes first, the Realtor or the lender?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which came first: the chicken or the egg? In a similar vein, when thinking about buying a property, do you contact the lender or a Realtor first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk about this in my book, “How to Buy a House in Houston, TX,” which I guess makes me the chicken!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice is to contact your Realtor first.&lt;/strong&gt; We have worked with the good, the bad, and the ugly. We’ve done the research so that you don’t have to! Instead of spending countless hours online, contact a human instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our personalized buyer consultations will put you right where you need to be to achieve your real estate goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how to get ready to buy a property, contact me today! I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 04:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-should-you-contact-a-realtor-or-lender-first.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-should-you-contact-a-realtor-or-lender-first.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5539 Lymbar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWRPiECqmI8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of a kind custom built, with fabulous finishes and details. Oversized garage, plenty of storage space and a massive back yard to entertain family and friends. NEVER FLOODED and not even in the 100 year floodplain. 4-5 bedrooms, primary bedroom on the first floor. Will enchant the pickiest of buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 10:45:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5539-lymbar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5539-lymbar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Can You Find at My Latest Open House?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H8QWijBx10k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’re invited to my latest open house at 5539 Lymbar Drive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a brand-new listing coming onto the market this weekend, and I want to invite you to a preview open house tomorrow to get your feedback and let you bring any buyers who might be interested. It’s located at 5539 Lymbar Drive and features 3,500 square feet of flex space that allows you to turn any room into anything you want. Additionally, it’s outside of the 500-year flood plain and within walking distance of JCC. To find out more, watch the short video above. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-can-you-find-at-my-latest-open-house.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-can-you-find-at-my-latest-open-house.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Is The Park at Highland Pines Coming Along?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T37sXOkRnCM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s nothing better than seeing a neighborhood come together.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m joined once again by Sergio Salazar, the general contractor working on The Park at Highland Pines, an exciting new development that we’re proud to represent. Sergio, who has more than 20 years of building experience under his belt, shared the latest progress Calidad Builders has made so far on the development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid imposing on the city sewer system, Sergio and his team have updated the development’s storm drainage to direct rainwater into a retention pond in the back, so it can be slowly drained into the city’s system. &lt;strong&gt;Sergio and his team have implemented all of the utilities and are gearing up to start on the streets.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Despite paperwork and minor delays, The Park at Highland Pines is shaping up nicely.%20http://localhost:4000/q-how-is-the-park-at-highland-pines-coming-along.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Despite paperwork and minor delays, The Park at Highland Pines is shaping up nicely.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the challenges he’s faced so far? As is no surprise when dealing with large-scale projects that need city approval and collaboration, paperwork has been a thorn in everyone’s side; luckily, the subcontractor for the utilities has been stellar and worked through various delays on the part of surveyors and other city inspectors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had a chance to speak with Jonathan Arrendendo, service consultant for CenterPoint Energy (2:18 in the video above). His job is to meet with customers to make sure their needs are being met. He also oversees the installation of transformers for new townhomes like the ones being built here at The Park. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to pour the streets, and after that, foundations will be built—&lt;strong&gt;it’ll be so awesome to finally see some of these beauties popping up!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We filmed this a few months ago, so if you have questions about this development or anything else relating to real estate, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send an email. We’re always here to help. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 13:26:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-is-the-park-at-highland-pines-coming-along.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-is-the-park-at-highland-pines-coming-along.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Who’s Building The Park at Highland Pines?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e-apPI6OFbQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m introducing the head builder of The Park at Highland Pines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back at The Park at Highland Pines, a 32-acre townhome development in a fully gated community with a huge dog park in the back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I’m taking you on a journey of the entire process of building this subdivision. I also want to introduce you to the builder, Sergio Salazar from Calidad Builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio started building in 2001 with his father. While he was in school at Texas A&amp;amp;M Monday through Thursday, he was helping build his parents’ custom home on the weekends. &lt;strong&gt;After that, he and his father did a couple of spec properties and started to build custom homes professionally in 2009.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Park at Highland Pines is his most ambitious project to date.%20http://localhost:4000/q-whos-building-the-park-at-highland-pines.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Park at Highland Pines is his most ambitious project to date.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio loves the feeling of accomplishment he gets after creating a home or development from nothing. As you can see in the video above, it’s all dirt now. However, the project will be finishing up very soon and we can’t wait for you to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calidad Builders is known for their quality, and that quality is evident in this project,&lt;/strong&gt; even if it’s a little different than what they did in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about The Park at Highland Pines, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I’d also be happy to help answer any questions you may have. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 17:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-whos-building-the-park-at-highland-pines.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-whos-building-the-park-at-highland-pines.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What’s the Progress at The Park at Highland Pines?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9gE5kjK0N00?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s an update on our latest new home development in Highland Pines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re back with the third episode of our series showcasing The Park at Highland Pines, a 32-townhome community in the heart of Acre Homes. Sergio Salazar from Calidad Builders is joining me to talk a bit about what has happened in the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We recently finished the infrastructure for the development, including the water, sewer, and electrical systems.&lt;/strong&gt; Now that it’s done, we’re ready to build our first model homes. We’re very excited about working with Sergio because he has so much custom home building experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These are going to be gorgeous custom homes.%20http://localhost:4000/q-whats-the-progress-at-the-park-at-highland-pines.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These are going to be gorgeous custom homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio’s expertise is really what makes this development special. For those looking for a high-quality, custom-designed home under the $300,00 price point, this is the location for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only are you getting a custom-designed home, but you also get to live in a space with some great amenities. For example, the retention pond in the back is required by the city, but Sergio is turning it into a nice dog park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acre Homes is an up-and-coming location in Houston&lt;/strong&gt; with retail, restaurants, entertainment, and more. Get in while you can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about The Park at Highland Pines or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-whats-the-progress-at-the-park-at-highland-pines.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-whats-the-progress-at-the-park-at-highland-pines.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Woman-to-Woman Interview With Houston Icon Bertie Simmons</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oSg476XTNMY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a sorrowful 10-year-old, Bertie Simmons swore she would fight for social justice here in Houston and across the nation. Today she shares a little bit of her story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of sitting down with an iconic Houstonian: Dr. Bertie Simmons. After nearly 60 years of working as a trailblazing educator in the Houston Independent School District, Bertie published her memoir, “Whispers of Hope: The Story of My Life,” which incorporates previously written recollections of her impactful childhood friendship with a black girl in the Jim Crow South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From raising funds to take gang-affiliated students to New York shortly after 9/11, to growing up in a toxic home environment, to the secret power of blueberries, Bertie and I covered it all in this open and honest woman-to-woman interview. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of our discussion with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:40 - Bertie’s childhood friendship with a black girl named Dorothy during the Jim Crow Era, witnessing the horrors of the Ku Klux Klan, and her calling to fight for social justice &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:55 - Bertie’s life in Houston: A commitment to fighting inequality in minority neighborhoods, her experience working with Barbara Bush and Clyde Drexler, and leaving a legacy for her granddaughter Ashley &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:10 - Bertie’s secret to staying youthful and energetic: blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:58 - Laurene Powell Jobs’ $10 million dollar donation &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:15 - Bertie addresses gang activity in her school and leads a humbling trip to Ground Zero &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:28 - Why Bertie decided to write a memoir &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:27 - Bertie addresses her removal from principalship at Furr High School and her subsequent lawsuit &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27:37 - Bertie’s message for us &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/woman-to-woman-interview-with-houston-icon-bertie-simmons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/woman-to-woman-interview-with-houston-icon-bertie-simmons.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We’re Supporting Our Community</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/43C0oN5PtBQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We want to give back during these uncertain times. If you’ve been directly affected by this pandemic, we would be happy to list your home for free. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’re staying safe (and sane!) during this challenging time. We want to support our community, so if you have lost your job due to the coronavirus or the oil and gas downturn, we will list your home for &lt;u&gt;FREE&lt;/u&gt;. We will include a 3D Matterport tour so buyers can virtually walk through your home without stepping foot in it. This is in addition to our regular services which include professional staging and photography. We’re looking forward to being able to host traditional open houses again, but in the meantime, please remember you can “ask us anything.” To hear more about what we’re doing to help, watch the video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-were-supporting-our-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-were-supporting-our-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trust Us When Buying Your New Home - We Know How to Play the Game!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jqSV2fyeVpc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Of course you need the right Realtor to help you buy a home, but they must have the right team around them to make the process smooth. Here&amp;rsquo;s how our team works.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game of buying a home has a few clear rules—that’s why, in order to play and win, you need to have the right team on your side. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s how our team takes transactions from start to finish.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two people involved in the process are your Realtor and lender. Realtors make sure that you’re prepared to make the best purchase possible. Lenders help guide you through the home-buying process while also keeping your budget and priorities in mind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The home inspector’s job is to protect your investment.%20http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The home inspector’s job is to protect your investment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once we have the right numbers to work with, we’ll send you a bunch of homes that meet your criteria and then help you make a competitive offer on the right home. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your contract is accepted, the title company will receive that contract, begin the title search, and produce their title commitment, which will be sent to all parties in the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home inspector then comes in to protect your investment. They’re here to make sure there is nothing wrong with the home’s structure or its systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, you’ll prepare for life’s unexpected happenings by securing home insurance. Flood insurance isn’t always required, but every home in Houston is in a flood zone, so you should strongly consider it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, it’s back to the title company so they can handle things behind the scenes and make sure all the details are there to run smoothly. Then it’s time for an appraisal. Finally, we make sure that you’re set up with the one-year home warranty that we offer to all our buyers at closing. &lt;strong&gt;Should systems fail to normal wear and tear, this warranty covers all replacements.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it’s time for the final walk through, get funded, and close and move. As you can see, none of us dropped the ball for the entire video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big thanks to our friends and partners at Supreme Lending, Allegiance Title, Red Star Inspections, Stewart Insurance, First American Home Warranty, and One Source Moving for helping us show how the perfect team works in harmony.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or any of our partners, feel free to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
