<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Broker Team</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams is to be your best resource for Houston real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams, your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 10:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 10:07:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Woman-to-Woman Interview With Houston Icon Bertie Simmons</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oSg476XTNMY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a sorrowful 10-year-old, Bertie Simmons swore she would fight for social justice here in Houston and across the nation. Today she shares a little bit of her story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of sitting down with an iconic Houstonian: Dr. Bertie Simmons. After nearly 60 years of working as a trailblazing educator in the Houston Independent School District, Bertie published her memoir, “Whispers of Hope: The Story of My Life,” which incorporates previously written recollections of her impactful childhood friendship with a black girl in the Jim Crow South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From raising funds to take gang-affiliated students to New York shortly after 9/11, to growing up in a toxic home environment, to the secret power of blueberries, Bertie and I covered it all in this open and honest woman-to-woman interview. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of our discussion with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:40 - Bertie’s childhood friendship with a black girl named Dorothy during the Jim Crow Era, witnessing the horrors of the Ku Klux Klan, and her calling to fight for social justice &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:55 - Bertie’s life in Houston: A commitment to fighting inequality in minority neighborhoods, her experience working with Barbara Bush and Clyde Drexler, and leaving a legacy for her granddaughter Ashley &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:10 - Bertie’s secret to staying youthful and energetic: blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:58 - Laurene Powell Jobs’ $10 million dollar donation &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:15 - Bertie addresses gang activity in her school and leads a humbling trip to Ground Zero &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:28 - Why Bertie decided to write a memoir &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:27 - Bertie addresses her removal from principalship at Furr High School and her subsequent lawsuit &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27:37 - Bertie’s message for us &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 17:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/woman-to-woman-interview-with-houston-icon-bertie-simmons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/woman-to-woman-interview-with-houston-icon-bertie-simmons.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We’re Supporting Our Community</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/43C0oN5PtBQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We want to give back during these uncertain times. If you’ve been directly affected by this pandemic, we would be happy to list your home for free. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’re staying safe (and sane!) during this challenging time. We want to support our community, so if you have lost your job due to the coronavirus or the oil and gas downturn, we will list your home for &lt;u&gt;FREE&lt;/u&gt;. We will include a 3D Matterport tour so buyers can virtually walk through your home without stepping foot in it. This is in addition to our regular services which include professional staging and photography. We’re looking forward to being able to host traditional open houses again, but in the meantime, please remember you can “ask us anything.” To hear more about what we’re doing to help, watch the video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-were-supporting-our-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-were-supporting-our-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trust Us When Buying Your New Home - We Know How to Play the Game!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jqSV2fyeVpc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Of course you need the right Realtor to help you buy a home, but they must have the right team around them to make the process smooth. Here&amp;rsquo;s how our team works.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game of buying a home has a few clear rules—that’s why, in order to play and win, you need to have the right team on your side. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s how our team takes transactions from start to finish.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two people involved in the process are your Realtor and lender. Realtors make sure that you’re prepared to make the best purchase possible. Lenders help guide you through the home-buying process while also keeping your budget and priorities in mind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The home inspector’s job is to protect your investment.%20http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The home inspector’s job is to protect your investment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once we have the right numbers to work with, we’ll send you a bunch of homes that meet your criteria and then help you make a competitive offer on the right home. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your contract is accepted, the title company will receive that contract, begin the title search, and produce their title commitment, which will be sent to all parties in the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home inspector then comes in to protect your investment. They’re here to make sure there is nothing wrong with the home’s structure or its systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time, you’ll prepare for life’s unexpected happenings by securing home insurance. Flood insurance isn’t always required, but every home in Houston is in a flood zone, so you should strongly consider it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, it’s back to the title company so they can handle things behind the scenes and make sure all the details are there to run smoothly. Then it’s time for an appraisal. Finally, we make sure that you’re set up with the one-year home warranty that we offer to all our buyers at closing. &lt;strong&gt;Should systems fail to normal wear and tear, this warranty covers all replacements.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it’s time for the final walk through, get funded, and close and move. As you can see, none of us dropped the ball for the entire video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big thanks to our friends and partners at Supreme Lending, Allegiance Title, Red Star Inspections, Stewart Insurance, First American Home Warranty, and One Source Moving for helping us show how the perfect team works in harmony.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or any of our partners, feel free to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 10:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trust-us-when-buying-your-new-home-we-know-how-to-play-the-game.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways You Can Save Money as a Homeowner in 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EW0X4_n0dxs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to save money as a homeowner in 2020, there are a couple of ways you can do so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if you currently live in your primary residence—not an investment property—&lt;strong&gt;you can file for homestead exemption.&lt;/strong&gt; The deadline to file is coming up fast, though, and keep in mind that you must have lived in your current home as of January 1 of this year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To file for this exemption, you can either go &lt;a href=&quot;http://hcad.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; or download the application and submit it via mail. In the latter case, you’ll need a copy of your driver’s license with your primary residence listed. The filing process is completely free, so don’t fall for any spam mail that offers to file for you for a nominal fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You might be surprised at how much of a reduction you get, and who doesn't want that extra cash in their pocket?%20http://localhost:4000/2-ways-you-can-save-money-as-a-homeowner-in-2020.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You might be surprised at how much of a reduction you get, and who doesn’t want that extra cash in their pocket?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way you can save money is by &lt;strong&gt;protesting your property taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; Property taxes tend to increase every year, but you can protest yours by bringing a copy of your property tax disclosure to the courthouse in person. Texas is a non-disclosure state, so remember that you’re not required to reveal how much you paid for your property. As with filing for homestead exemption, this process is free. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like help protesting your property taxes, I would be happy to do a comparative market analysis of your local area to supplement your position. In any case, don’t be afraid to give it a shot. You might be surprised at how much of a reduction you get, and who doesn’t want that extra cash in their pocket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;homestead-exemption-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hcad.org/hcad-forms/hcad-popular-forms/?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Homestead Exemption Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the County Link to view the Homestead Exemption Forms. This form can be filled from &lt;strong&gt;Jan 1st - April 30th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://t.e2ma.net/click/9q630e/lw2pzcb/xt89w3&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1579873931759000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFGJJ0EGzhxuPzsibxCWOmy5bQrig&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harris County Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brazoriacad.org/all-property-tax-forms.html?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brazoria County Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fbcad.org/Forms-Submissions/Forms?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fort Bend Central Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.galvestoncad.org/index.php/Forms?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Galveston Central Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mcad-tx.org/Forms?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Montgomery Central Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waller-cad.org/index.php/Local_Forms?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Waller County Appraisal District&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hcad-mobile-app&quot;&gt;HCAD Mobile App&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/harris-county-appraisal-district/id1056225999?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IOS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.localgsa.HcadPublicA&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now electronically file your residential homestead exemption online utilizing the HCAD Mobile App.   To submit the homestead application utilizing the mobile app, you will need 4 items: &lt;br /&gt;1 - The date of occupancy on your residence.   &lt;br /&gt;2 - Your TX drivers license  &lt;br /&gt;3 - An iPhone or Android phone   &lt;br /&gt;4 - The HCAD Info and Exemptions app (found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/harris-county-appraisal-district/id1056225999?utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.localgsa.HcadPublicA&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;utm_source=BenchmarkEmail&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Don%27t_Forget_to_File_Your_Homestead_Exemption_January_2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-ways-you-can-save-money-as-a-homeowner-in-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2-ways-you-can-save-money-as-a-homeowner-in-2020.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Tips for a Successful Home Flip</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dsuAsG_-xgc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flipping homes can be a lucrative industry, but if you think it’ll be as easy as it looks on HGTV, you’re in for a rude awakening. However, there are a few tips that professionals utilize to maximize the outcome of their projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some flippers &lt;strong&gt;hire a good contractor&lt;/strong&gt; to come to the property and do the repairs. These contractors are reliable and follow timelines. I’d recommend that you look for contractors before you even start looking for a property to flip. I’d be happy to recommend one to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flippers also know to &lt;strong&gt;buy in the right neighborhoods.&lt;/strong&gt; Just because a property is cheap, that doesn’t necessarily make it a good buy. You want to make sure that the values in the neighborhood are rising, that it’s in a good school district, and that there are other desirable features of the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Just because a property is cheap, that doesn’t necessarily make it a good buy.%20http://localhost:4000/my-tips-for-a-successful-home-flip.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Just because a property is cheap, that doesn’t necessarily make it a good buy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other flippers do much of the work themselves; &lt;strong&gt;instead of hiring a contractor, they take on the work themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; I know your time has a lot of value, but bad renovations can really turn off potential buyers for that house. Good flippers understand that the property is an investment, but they also want a quick turnaround. Instead of focusing on getting the most beautiful finishes, I’d personally recommend that you keep all the renovations generic and appealing to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about what makes for a good flip or investment property, or if you’re looking for a contractor to help you with your next flip, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-tips-for-a-successful-home-flip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-tips-for-a-successful-home-flip.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Houston Broker Team: Who We Are</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/psCMqZrrzvU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re the Houston Broker Team, and we’d like to tell you a little bit about ourselves: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re fighters who go the extra mile, and we’ve always got your back. Our detailed buyer consultation helps us to determine your real estate goals from the jump, so &lt;strong&gt;we can surpass your expectations.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to purchasing a home, we wrote the book—quite literally (“How to Buy a House in Houston, TX” by Daniela Antelo). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 25 years of combined real estate experience, we can point you in the right direction. From selecting the best lender to getting your house keys, we’re there with you every step of the way; no transaction is too big or small for our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When it comes to purchasing a home, we wrote the book—quite literally.%20http://localhost:4000/the-houston-broker-team-who-we-are.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When it comes to purchasing a home, we wrote the book—quite literally.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our sellers, we have a very strategic 10-point marketing strategy that will get your home sold for the highest price possible with the least amount of time. &lt;strong&gt;Our extensive network and use of technology will set you up to win.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Houston Broker Team developed the HBT exclusive pre-listing review to get your home sold even before it hits the market; our open houses attract more traffic than any traditional open house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With database management, client appreciation, and community building, we make sure nothing falls through the cracks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach out to the Houston Broker Team today and find out how we can help with your real estate goals and you’ll end up with a trusted real estate advisor for life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-houston-broker-team-who-we-are.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-houston-broker-team-who-we-are.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the 5 Factors That Influence a Home’s Asking Price?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A-XjqyE53-U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing a home is part science, part art, and understanding the reasoning behind this pricing will make you a smarter buyer and help you understand exactly what you’re getting for your money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before sticking a “For Sale” sign in front of a home, here are the five factors Realtors look at when pricing it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What’s happening in your local market.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate conditions can change quickly, so understanding what’s going on now is very important. For example, how fast are properties being snapped up? Is it a buyer’s or seller’s market? Low inventory means it’s a seller’s market and there’s more room to push prices up, while high inventory means it’s a buyer’s market. Our market, in particular, can change quickly, so you need to keep yourself updated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The specific location of the home.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not just talking about its ZIP code—I’m talking about whether there are good schools nearby, it sits in a cul-de-sac or backs up to a busy street, etc. It’s worth noting that in most areas, homes that have easier access to a highway fetch a higher sale price.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. A comparative market analysis.&lt;/strong&gt; Oftentimes, sellers will already have a number in mind when I meet them for a listing presentation, and this number isn’t necessarily the most accurate. Homeowners tend to develop an emotional attachment to their homes over time and think it’s worth more than it is. A Realtor will be able to look at comparable properties on the MLS that have sold in the past six months to give the home a comparative market analysis. The MLS provides a lot of good information for this purpose, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The home’s amenities (and overall appeal).&lt;/strong&gt; Today’s buyers look at more than just a home’s square footage. Most of the time, they prefer brand-name appliances, larger bedrooms and closets, lots of light, central air conditioning, outdoor space, easy parking, and, in general, new construction over older homes. Layout and functionality are also huge pluses in terms of desirability, which means older homes that aren’t upgraded will be priced lower. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Whether or not it’s a fixer-upper.&lt;/strong&gt; You won’t get a lower price just because you’re thinking of buying a fixer-upper—location plays a big role in pricing these types of homes too. On the other hand, if you’re buying a newer turnkey property, expect to pay more for it because quality trumps quantity every time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Real estate conditions can change quickly, so understanding what’s going on now is very important.%20http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-5-factors-that-influence-a-homes-asking-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Real estate conditions can change quickly, so understanding what’s going on now is very important.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how homes are priced or you’re a seller and you want to know what your home is worth, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-5-factors-that-influence-a-homes-asking-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-5-factors-that-influence-a-homes-asking-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Homebuyer’s Guide to Researching Schools</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GFkCjWITl80?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have children who are going to school, it will, of course, play a big part in your decision about what house to buy. But how do you know which schools are best for your children?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well first, don’t pick a house only because it’s in a particular school zone, since that can change at any moment. A school that had an A+ rating one year could have a C- rating a few years later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I recommend to those searching for a new home and school to consider these four points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take your child’s needs into account.&lt;/strong&gt; Are they better off in a larger-room environment or in a smaller classroom setting?  Are they going to need any special programming? Do they participate in extracurricular activities? Really study what educational facets your child needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Decide when the best time to move will be.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to come up with an exact date, but if you’re looking for your child to start school in the fall and be able to immerse themselves, it’s best to start looking at properties in the summertime. This is a great time to allow you to transition into the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Research schools online.&lt;/strong&gt; One website I recommend is www.GreatSchools.org. This is a national nonprofit website that offers all sorts of information about schools, including rankings, parental feedback, and more. It’s a good place to start building a community and educating yourself on the schools you might consider for your child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re looking for your child to start school in the fall and be able to immerse themselves, it’s best to start looking at properties in the summertime.%20http://localhost:4000/a-homebuyers-guide-to-researching-schools.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re looking for your child to start school in the fall and be able to immerse themselves, it’s best to start looking at properties in the summertime.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Visit a school in person.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you step into the school, you’ll get a sense for the environment that your child might experience. You’ll also have an opportunity to speak with staff to get an idea about class sizes, etc., and to speak to other parents about their experiences. This is the time to ask the hard questions, like about the school’s policies for handling discipline and safety issues, the extracurricular activities offered, how they use technology to assist the teaching process, and similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A happy child is part of a successful move, so be sure to do your homework in advance. You can compare your needs and lifestyle to the information you’ve gathered from the schools, helping you to make a successful match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how to connect with schools or how to find this information online, reach out to me today. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-homebuyers-guide-to-researching-schools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-homebuyers-guide-to-researching-schools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You must Know Before Starting Your Home Remodel</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gSSXRxAZOPs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people assume that remodeling a home is a good idea, and for the most part, they’re right. If you’re thinking of remodeling your home, though, there are certain factors you need to take into account to make it a successful project. To help you with this, I’m interviewing homeowners and recent remodeler Vivianna Laprea inside her own house so she can share her experience and give you further insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow along in the video above to see our full conversation. For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so you can skip ahead to various sections: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:08—Qualifications to seek out and red flags to watch for when hiring a contractor &lt;br /&gt;1:53—How important is an architect in the remodeling process?&lt;br /&gt;2:17—What you can do ahead of time to make your project more affordable &lt;br /&gt;2:50—Preparing your timeline &lt;br /&gt;3:32—Vivianna’s original timeline versus the actual timeline &lt;br /&gt;4:23—Which areas they put more money into for resale purposes &lt;br /&gt;5:39—What she learned doing this project and what she would do differently if she could do it again&lt;br /&gt;6:49—The top tips she would give to someone embarking on a remodel &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about this topic or you’re thinking of remodeling your home, don’t hesitate to get in touch with me. I’d be happy to guide you through the process. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 14:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-must-know-before-starting-your-home-remodel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-you-must-know-before-starting-your-home-remodel.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Join Us for a Dinner With the Dumpling Dudez</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rCIRqLYgjgw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s November—and that means it’s also Gratitude Month. With so much of our business being referral-based, we want to give back to all of you for your continued support. We’re doing it by hosting a dinner party with the Dumpling Dudez. For the entire month of November, if you send us a referral of someone looking to buy, sell, or lease a property in Houston, you’ll be entered into a drawing. 10 lucky winners will be picked on November 30 to come to this dinner in January. If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-join-us-for-a-dinner-with-the-dumpling-dudez.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-join-us-for-a-dinner-with-the-dumpling-dudez.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
